MISTY DERAMUS

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

1 256-490-4443

in www.linkedin.com/in/misty-deramus

19 https://github.com/mderamus

≥ mistyderamus@gmail.com

https://mderamus19.github.io

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Software development is a career field I wanted to pursue for over 20 years. I began college as a Computer Science major; however, I decided to go into Social Work. Working as a Social Worker allowed me to help others but it did not diminish my desire to be a software developer. So I ventured to earn an Associate Degree in Computer Science. As a member of the Air Force, I continued to work as a Social Worker. After a rewarding career in Social Work, I decided to pursue my passion of becoming a Software developer. Software development gives me the opportunity to work with clients and mentor others as I increase my developer skills. I chose Nashville Software School because of its intense training model, diversity and business relationship with the professional technical community.

PROJECTS

Dreamer To Achiever Front End Project

I host an action board event that entails creating goals and steps by placing them on a cork board. Dreamer to Achiever is a simple application developed to allow users to track their goals on an electronic device. The user can enter a goal and steps needed to complete the goals. The user is able to edit, delete and save the goal and steps. Once the goal is achieved, the user is able to choose a reward from a drop down menu for completion of the goal. Styled application with CSS Frameworks, Bootstrap and Reactstrap. The application was developed using ReactJS.

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School

Software Development Bootcamp May 2019–November 2019

Alabama A&M University

MSW, Social Work 2003–2006

Gadsden State Community College

AAS, Computer Science 2000–2001

University of Alabama

BSW, Social Work 1992–1996

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

Nashville Software School

May 2019 - Nov 2019

• An intensive six-month rigorous program with individual and team-based projects using technologies.

Front-end Development:

- Utilized Git and Github for version control of applications, code, and documentation.
- Established a Github profile to showcase individual and team-based projects.
- Utilized HTML5, CSS3, and Flexbox to markup, style and design the personal life page of the Celebrity Tribute team–based project.
- Incorporated Javascript, HTML, JSON, Ticketmaster API, modular, and DOM manipulation to develop an application of an itinerary for a day trip to Nashville.
- Established verbal and written communication skills throughout the life of the project.

Back End Development:

- Server-side development fundamentals with python
- Application design by white board dependencies
- Worked in agile environment including debugging, ticketing, stand-ups, pairprogramming and retrospectives
- Bangazon LLC sprint-1 included building features defined in the backlog to create a single web application using python, SQL, Django, Git, and Github.

Licensed Independent Clinical Social Worker, PRN

May 2016 - Present

Children's Aid Society

- Technology used: MS Word
- Assessed and qualified families for adoption

Medical Social Worker, PRN

Apr 2017 - Present

LHC Group

- Technology used: Point Care
- Conducted Biopsychosocial assessments
- Coordinated client services for community resources



☐ 256-490-4443
in www.linkedin.com/in/misty-deramus
 https://github.com/mderamus19
 mistyderamus@gmail.com
 https://mderamus19.github.io

Work Experience continued

Military and Family Life Counselor

Apr 2014 - Jun 2019

Magellan Health

- Educated Army National Guard for Pre and Post Deployment
- Provided Solution Focused Therapy to youth and school age children to assist with adjustment to the military lifestyle
- Incorporated conflict resolution to staff members

Medical Social Worker

Apr 2013 - Apr 2015

Hospice Advantage

- Provided on the job training and supervision for licensure
- Assessed pre-bereavement needs, anticipatory grief needs and completed end of life review with patients

Licensed Clinical Social Worker

Oct 2011 - Sep 2012

Sterling Medical Staffing Group

- Technologies used: Alta Medical Management System and MS Word
- Conducted psycho-social assessments to determine a diagnosis, develop treatment plans and refer for medications
- Facilitated therapy sessions to manage depression, anxiety and enhance client coping skills, relapse prevention and lifestyle changes

Director of Social Services

Sep 2010 - Sep 2011

East Glen Nursing Facility

- Technologies used: MDS (Minimum Data Set) and MS Word
- Provided clinical consultation, advocacy, outreach, referral and discharge planning to clients experiencing mental health issues or requiring home health/hospice services
- Implemented departmental policies and service procedures

U.S. Air Force Jul 2008 – Aug 2010

Family Advocacy Program Manager

- Supervised employees; conducted training, mentored growth, and provided guidance in handling difficult or complex situations
- Handled confidential data and records; ensured the integrity of documents and sustained compliance with HIPAA, HSI (Health Services Inspection) and JCAHO standards
- Consultant to physicians for non compliant patients
- Approved exceptional family members for assignments to meet their unique needs
- Evaluated employee performance and wrote reports for upper management; discussed areas of concern with personnel and resolved problems
- Provided Air Force Family Advocacy Program (FAP) case management services focused on spouse and child abuse; received initial referrals, conducted intake interviews, and made psycho-social assessments